who did you vote for? It does
за кого голосовали Да ни за кого всё
n't matter for anyone. I know everyone knows about Putin. And
равно Знаю я за Путина все знают сри А
why are you doing this? I'm just curious. I don't
зачем ты вот просто мне интересно я не
know why you vote for Putin. If you
знаю зачем голосовать за Путина Если ты
see that there's nothing really for Russia,
видишь что ничего толком нету для России
well, that's understandable. So why did you
ну это понятное дело Так а зачем
vote for him?  I know And who to
голосовал за него не знаю А за кого
do went to put a tick left everything is
делать пошёл галочку поставил ушёл всё
so simple well if look for example if
так просто ну если смотри например если
I have like yes for example in Ukraine
вот у меня типа да например в Украине
when I don't like the president I
когда мне не нравится президент Я
vote for someone else to
голосую за кого-то другого чтобы
change
поменять
him
его
Oh hello let's have a normal
О здравствуйте давайте нормально
conversation
пообщаемся
let's Yes I look I  I don't quarrel with people
давай Да я смотрите я не ссорюсь людьми
from Russia I am from Ukraine city
из России Я сам из Украины город
Khmelnitsky where are you from Rostov
Хмельницкий Вы откуда С Ростовской
region Wow Cool my father is
области Вау Прикольно у меня отец родом
from Shakhty and where are you from Rostov
из города Шахты А вы откуда С Ростовской
region with s fly not seriously
области с с муха не серьёзно
Well
Ну город
Moroz city type we have a person living
Мороз городского типа у нас человек жит
here small city Shakhty  us shoes
тут небольшой город Шахты у нас туфли
there
там
business
дела
bar
баром
did vodka area there in the
делали водку область туда в
side m you communicate
сторо м общаетесь
About what about what everything understood Look And by
О чём о чём всём понял Смотри А у Вас
the way do you have any acquaintances
кстати у вас есть какие-то знакомые
who  at war or have already come from
которые на войне или уже пришли с
war not not
войны не не
at all about acquaintances yes like A there are those
вообще про знакомых да типа А есть такие
who died or are already wounded
которые погибли или раненые уже есть
there are Christmas trees and sticks but there are
есть ёлки-палки а
many yes enough lags there are many in the
много да достаточно лагов много на
cemetery that what
кладбище что что
flags on the cl
флагов на кла деньгами
most went for money went for money and
пошли большинство за деньгами пошли и
died And how many  they were promised Well, how much
погибли А сколько им обещали Ну сколько
200 something they pay per month like per month
200 с чем-то платят в месяц типа в месяц
and they Yes I
и они Да
go there for a month there something there immediately
иду меся там го там что-то там сразу
went something million 2 they pay Yes something
пошл что-то ляма 2 платят Да что-то
like that if immediately half Yes there are different things
такое если сразу пол Да там по-разному
well in short  do
ну короче
you have any relatives
а у вас какие-то родственники есть
who also went
которые тоже пошли
somewhere Of course
где-то Конечно
there are living ones
есть живые
died died pain
погибли погиб боль
died Rostov trucks arrived with
погибли Ростов фуры приехали с
corpses this is
трупами это
when And how can we
когда А чем мы
help Yes we say in any case Yes my
поможем Да мы говорим по-любому Да мне
dad told me two trucks just brought
вот батя говорил две фуры вот привезли
They brought Well what  The boys Yes, they died Well, they
Привезли Ну что Пацаны Да погибли Да ну
stupidly went for money Well, what,
по глупости пошли за деньгами Ну что
many, many, and what do their parents
много много а а что их родители
say And what will they say, they
говорят А что они что они скажет ничего
can't say anything Who's gone crazy,
не могут сказать У кого Куку поехала у
who's got nerves Well, if you
кого нервы Ну если родственников родных
lose relatives, you yourself understand  I
потерять сам понимает как-то
somehow understood it and we
так понял а нам это
need it I think we don't need it But you don't
надо Я думаю не надо Но вам тоже не
need it either it's just like that it also turns out I
надо так просто тоже получается Я
think I think like it turns out yes That
думаю я думаю типа получается да Что
Russia is such a rich country and gold
Россия Такая богатейшая страна и золото
oil gas diamonds and people have to
нефть газ алмазы а приходится людям
go and die to earn money
чтобы заработать деньги ехать умирать
like that too
типа это тоже
somehow it happens like that and somehow my
как-то бывает так и и както у меня Бат
Batya told me Well, I didn't live in the
батя рассказывал Ну я я не жил в
Rostov region Yes, my dad is
Ростовской области Да у меня батя он
from there Shahnets he says that
оттуда родом Шах нец он говорит что
when like during the Soviet Union yes, then the work was
когда типа при Союзе да то работа была
normal, people earned money, lived, yes
нормально зарабатывали жили люди дало да
And now it seems  damn, Russia also
А сейчас вроде блин тож есть у России
has oil, gold, mines, diamonds, everything,
остались нефть золото Шахты алмазы всё
take it, in short, damn, I provide for people. Yes,
есть бери короче блин людей обеспечиваю
that's somewhere there. And did you
Да это там где-то
go to the elections, yeah. Yes, it happened once,
А а на выборы ходили ага Да как-то было
and who did you
а за кого
vote for? Who did you vote for? Dani, for
голосовали За кого голосовали Дани за
whom? The Supreme Court doesn't
кого ВС равно
know why, just  I'm interested I don't know
зна зачем просто мне интересно я не знаю
why vote for Putin If you
зачем голосовать за Путина Если ты
see that there is nothing really for
видишь что ничего толком нету для
Russia it's clear
России это понятное
why you voted for
дело зачем голосовал за
him not
него не
just well if look for example if
просто ну если смотри например если вот
I have like yes for example in Ukraine when
у меня типа да например в Украине когда
I don't like the president I  I vote for
мне не нравится президент Я голосую за
someone else to change him And
кого-то другого чтобы поменять его А
most people will vote for the one
большинство людей проголосуют за того
who Well, yes, but you would vote
которого Ну вот да но ты бы проголосовал
for the one who thinks And it turns out that
за того кто считает А так получается что
everyone went you don't vote you won't
каждый пошёл ты не про голосуешь ты не
vote will vote you think this
проголосует проголосует вы думайте этот
vote will give you something  Well, I think if
голос вас что-то даст Ну я думаю если
everyone thinks like that then it definitely won't give it
каждый так будет думать то точно не даст
definitely won't give it this is not
точно не даст это ни
us sitting here
ом мы сидим Вот так
hiccupping And what do you think Crimea is whose
икаем А как вы считаете Крым - это чей
Russia Ukraine should be Russia Russia
Россия Украина должен быть Россия Росси
Why Because Crimea is ours
Почему Потому что это Крым наш потому
because Dani all people say that  And what
что Дани все так люди говорят И тем
's more, they built a bridge there,
более там мост же
that's why from Crimea to
построили что нуча с Крыма во
You see, and it's still going on. Yes, he didn't
Видишь и оно тянется до сих пор Да он не
take it, it was ours. Wait, who was
забирал его это наши был Подожди Кто
Stalin or
Сталин или
who was Crimea. Well, how was Crimea? Look, it was
кто Крым Ну как Крым смотри девяносто
1991. Yes, Ukraine and Crimea have been living for 30 years
первый год да Украина с Крымом мы 30 лет
since Stalin. Let's go.  let's take this under the
жи Сталина Давайте возьмём Вот это под
command so
началь так
Stalin
Сталин бы
Gorbachev I don't remember already the
Горбач Я уже не помню уже
year or Stalin
го года или Сталин
Gorbachev
Горбач
Stalin what Stalin what Stalin
Сталин что Сталин что Сталин
[music]
[музыка]
did it how did
сделал это как
he
его украинскому
sell something to some Ukrainian  confused Well, first he
продал что-то запутался Ну он сначала
sold it to some
продал его как-то какому-то вашему
boss of yours, I forgot it in my memory, sold it,
начальнику я забыл уже в память продал
understood, and then he bought it back Well, I don't know
понял а потом его перекупил Ну не знаю
how it was About what And when he bought
как там Насчёт чего А когда он перекупил
it back, well, Stalin
его назад ну Сталин
Stalin Well, okay, look, Stalin I
Сталин Да ну хорошо смотри Сталин Я
just don't know  if I hadn't lived then I would have already I
просто не знаю бы я не жил тогда я уже Я
was born in the first year of the USSR yes
родился в воде первом году при СССР да
Crimea was already in Ukraine in the
Крым уже был в Украине в де
Ukraine was independent Russia all became different
Укра независи Россия все стали разными
states Crimea would have
государствами рым бы
sold Ukraine to Ukraine and then bought it out
Укра продал Украине а потом перекупил
or I don't know how or they paid off the debt I don't know
или не знаю как или задол отдали не знаю
what's there  this is the
что там вот это
slightest look 14 year Crimea in Ukraine and
малейшее смотри 14 год Крым в Украине и
Russia seizes it that no one sold it there
Россия его захватывает что там никто его
Well how 14 year the
продавал Ну как 14 год
first one still held there forty-six forty-
первый ещё держал там сорок шестой сорок
eight Stalin Stalin did not understand this yes
восьмой Сталин Сталин не это понял да А
But I mean when in
вот я имею в виду когда вот в
Ukraine he simply gave it to Ukraine and  then he
Украине просто отдал Украине а потом его
bought it out, that's it, he bought it out, Okay, okay, he
выкупил вот выкупил А хорошо Ну ладно он
bought it out, but look, in 2014, when
выкупил но смотрите в 2014 год когда был
Yanukovych was in Maidan, Yes, for example, Crimea was in
Янукович Майдан Да например Крым был в
Ukraine, Crimea was in Ukraine, Well, that's
Украине Крым был в Украине Ну вот во
how it ended up in Russia during Yanukovych's time
время Януковича получается как он попал
I can't
в Россию я не могу
understand don't
понять не
turn it off it's a pity awesome characters for
отключайте жалко офигенные персонажи для
m like Don't switch let's have a
м лайк Не переключайтесь давайте
normal conversation we saw you in
нормально пообщаемся мы вас видели
my opinion let's what you 18 years old there is
по-моему давайте что вам 18 лет есть
everything once 18 to look at me Can I
есть всё раз 18 на меня смотреть Можно я
allow I am from the city of Khmelnitsky Ukraine where are
разрешаю Я из города Хмельницке Украина
you from We are from Belgorod from
Вы откуда Мы из Белгорода из самого
Belgorod itself or from the
Белгорода или из области
Belgorod region But look, I know that now
Белгород А вот смотри я знаю что сейчас
Ukrainian troops are in the Kursk region and in
украинские войска в Курской области а в
Belgorod it is calm and calm and
Белгороде там спокойно да спокойно а то
what they said was shelling Belgorod
что говорили обстреливали Белгород
was shelled and they showed us I dont know if
обстреливали и нам показывали Я не знаю
its true or
это правда
not it flew and
неправда долетел и в Белгороде в
hit a five-story building in Belgorod no but  Ukrainian was
пятиэтажку попал нет зато украинский был
well as Ukrainian Czech drone
ну как украинский чешский беспилотник
so the mine was made in
так шахет был производство
the Czech Republic there they did an examination then the
Чехии там экспертизу потом сделали
drone was made in the Czech Republic No well it's clear
беспилотник производство че Не ну ясно
that they won't say that it was their own mine that
что они не скажут что это свой шахет
went off Well let it be a drone And
бахнул Ну пускай будет это беспилотник А
how is it there How is it there you often
как там Как там у вас сирены часто
turn on sirens when threatened Well once  per day once a
включает при угрозе Ну раз в день раз в
month how is it different at all it doesn't
месяц как вообще по-разному это не
depend on  something this just
зависит от чего-то это просто вот
happens involuntarily and how do you
непроизвольно происходи а как вы
feel about all this, we are tired of this war
относитесь к этому всему к этой войне
already Well, to be honest,
устали уже Мы Да ну честно говоря
I would like to live of course like before, well,
хотелось бы жить конечно как раньше ну
just so that I dont have to run to
просто хотя бы чтобы не бегать там в
shelter But in general, in principle, nothing has
укрытие А так вообще в принципе ничего
changed A  what do you think is the reason Well,
поменялось А как думаете из-за чего Ну
why do you have to run for
из-за чего Вам приходится сейчас бегать
cover now because such a situation And
укрытие потому что такая обстановка А
why such a situation I
почему такая обстановка Вот мне
wonder don't understand how people in
интересно несь Поня как Мыт люди в
Russia We understand Why why are we being shelled you
России Почему почему нас обстреливают вы
want to ask Well, yes, why from what are
хотите спросить Ну да почему из до чего
you being shelled  because two countries are fighting
вас обстреливают потому что воюют две
And why are two countries fighting? The
страны А почему воют две страны близкая
border territory is close to this country.
территория границы с этой страной Да ну
Well, I mean, look, 3 years
имею в виду вот смотрите там 3 года
ago, these countries weren't fighting, you weren't
назад страны эти не воевали вас не
being shelled. Who's to blame for you being
обстреливали кто виноват в том что вас
shelled? That's how you ask
обстреливают вот так вы спрашивать у
ordinary girls who are now  sitting in the
обычных девочек которые сечас сидят в с
house
доме
honestly speaking Not the Duma we just
честно говор Не Дума мы просто
woke up in the morning the war started
проснулись на утро началась война вот
just like you
так же как и вы
Yes for example if you ask me because of
Да например если меня спросить я из-за
whom the war started I will say because of Putin
кого началась война я скажу из-за Путина
Yes he attacked Ukraine that's it  Who do you
Да он напал на Украину вот а вы как
think started the war? He was the
считаете из-за кого началась война он
only one who ran with a fork. Not only he, but also your
один бежал с вилкою не только он да ваши
dads, grandfathers, some relatives
папы там дедушки какие-то родственники
ran with forks. So, what do you think?
бежали с вилками Да вот вы как считаете
Who is to blame for the war starting,
Кто виноват что началась война
for forcing our state to be the
что вынудили наше государство чтобы оно
first to go to those who  who is to blame
первое зашло на те кто виноват вот кто
who is to blame there is always no one
Кто конкретно виноват всегда есть никто
let's say it like this no one is
давайте мы скажем так никто не Никто
to blame it is if the daughter went natural
виноват это если доч пошёл природное
phenomenon let's say it like this no one is
явление давайте так скажем никто не
to blame not your country not ours but a
виноват не ваша страна не наша а
foreign country is to blame who
виноват посторонняя страна которая Кто
who exactly who is
Кто конкретно Кто
to blame Well the country that helps you
виноват Ну страна которая вам помогает
what  vatu
Какая вате
then America America that is America is
тогда Америка Америка то есть Америка
to blame that is I understand correctly that
виновата то есть я правильно понимаю что
America is to blame that Russia is bombing
Америка виновата что Россия бомбит
Ukraine No it is that Russia was the
Украину Нет это то что вторглась Россия
first to invade Ukraine and the fact that
первая в Украину а то что там вторглась
Russia invaded Ukraine but America is to blame
Россия в Украину но виновата Америка в
what is the logic just explain Well come on you
чём логика просто Объясните Да ну вы же
yourself  I understand perfectly well I
сами прекрасно понима не понимаю как раз
don't understand I just don't understand you understand perfectly well America
не понимаю прекрасно понимаете Америка
helped Ukraine and tried to put
помогала Украине и пыталась подставить
its weapons closer to the border with
свои своё оружие ближе к границе к
Russia so that
Российской чтобы
because
потому
NATO exists which poses a threat to the
существует НАТО которое несёт угрозу
state is it beneficial for the state
государству разве государству выгодно
when there is a threat how best to
когда существует угроза как лучше
eliminate the threat or exist with that
устранить угрозу или существовать с тем
that something irreversible might happen
что может случиться что-то необратимое
Well, I look, I understand I don't understand a little
Ну я смотри я понял Я немножко не
purely from the political side
понимаю чисто с политической стороны
purely from the political side not because there's
чисто с политической не с того что там
a war there It's a pity for the people we all understand the
война Очень жаль людей мы ВС понимаем
nights
ночи
that a war that we shouldn't enter into
че война в которую не должны вступать не
shouldn't enter into the People and I don't  I understand For
должен вступать Народ а я не понимаю Вот
example, Estonia, Latvia, Lithuania, they have been in NATO
например Эстония Латвия Литва они в НАТО
for a long time, they are Russia's neighbors, yes Why
давным-давно это соседи России да Почему
didn't Russia attack them, NATO was already
Россия не нападала на них так НАТО уже
there
там
because it doesn't pose a threat And
было потому что не представляет угрозы А
why is it that Estonia, which is just a
почему возле Эстония от которой до
stone's throw from St. Petersburg, doesn't pose a
Питера рукой подать не представляет
threat, but Ukraine
угрозу а Украина
does, well, that's it  that's how
представляет ну вот так сложились
the circumstances turned out I just can't
обстоятельства Просто я тоже не могу
understand you asking us why
понять нас спрашиваете почему
she didn't make a claim I don't make a claim to you
она не претензию я не претензию к вам
I'm interested in how they think because I'm a
Мне интересно как вот мыслят по что я
simple person I can talk to
простой человек Я могу поговорить с
simple people Yes, for example, a politician
простыми людьми Да например политик
can talk to a politician I can't
может поговорить с политиком я не могу
talk to Zelensky there  Poroshenko
поговорить с Зеленским там Порошенко
Putin And so on I can talk to
Путиным И так дальше я могу поговорить с
ordinary people What do you think what do I
простыми людьми Как вы думаете как я
think because we told how I think to
думаю потому что мы рассказали как думаю
ask the question Why because of what and who is
вопрос задавать Почему изза чего и кто
to blame as if we dont decide anything here
виноват как будто бы мы тут ничего не
it seems like you dont decide anything Yes but here
вот вроде ничего не решаете Да но тут
already  you start with TV cliches NATO
уже начинаете штампами телевизора НАТО
There and so on Where did you learn about
Там и так дальше Откуда вы узнали про
NATO Well you asked we answered you Well
НАТО Ну вы спросили мы вам ответили Ну
that is I mean they told you at school
то есть я имею в виду это вам в школе
at university on
рассказали в университете в
TV Well I mean sometime somewhere
телеви Ну име ввиду когда-то где-то
someone told you about NATO  told that it is
кто-то вам про НАТО рассказал что оно
dangerous or what And who has she ever
опасно или что А на кого она когда-то
attacked Well let's do it this way why does the
нападала Ну давайте так для чего вообще
Union of countries even exist look for example
существует Союз стран да смотри например
Russia yes Russia created its own military
Россия да Россия создала свой военный
bloc CSTO it includes Armenia Belarus
блок одкб туда входят Армения Белоруссия
Kazakhstan and others Yes
Казахстан и ещё другие Да
uh many countries  they enter into military blocs
ээ многие страны входят в военные блоки
in order to defend themselves together against
для того чтобы вместе защищаться от
aggression, these are defensive blocs, NATO is also a
агрессии это защитные блоки НАТО также
bloc that is
НАТО блок который
for defense, so that if someone
ээ для защиты для того чтобы если кто-то
attacks a NATO member, so that everyone can
нападёт на члена НАТО чтобы все вместе
defend together, that is, NATO is not for
защищать то есть НАТО - это не для
attacking someone  and for protection with
нападения на на кого-то а для защиты со
all
всё
let's
давай
go write to my Telegram right now
поехали пись на мий Telegram прям зараз
axis VN
ось ВН
apok this is very and very important YouTube takes
апок це дуже и дуже важливо YouTube заня
us through scarg ORV in your ban and very
нас через скарг ОРВ в твый бан и дуже
many videos  don't show people
багато вдео не показуе людям вчасно не
information about streams at times so
показуе информация про стримы тому для
that we can write the latest operational links
того щоб мы Мали оперативный звязок
right away and Popik there in
пишиться прямо зараз а Попик там в
telegram will give you videos that are also interesting and
телеграми окрим видео ще теж цикава и
useful information and we will oblige you
корисна информация и мы повинни з вами
to keep the latest operational links
тримати постийний оперативный звязок
independently so that we can show you the
незалежно в того чи покаже вам проце
YouTube process  Glory to Ukraine letter
YouTube Слава украини пись
with
с